[
    {
        "question": "What is the term used for describing the judgmental or commonsense part of problem solving?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Heuristic",
        "b": "Critical",
        "c": "Value based",
        "d": "Analytical",
        "answer": "Heuristic"
    },
    {
        "question": "What stage of the manufacturing process has been described as 'the mapping of function onto form'?",
        "a": "Design",
        "b": "Distribution",
        "c": "project management",
        "d": "field service",
        "answer": "Design"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which kind of planning consists of successive representations of different levels of a plan?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "hierarchical planning",
        "b": "non-hierarchical planning",
        "c": "All of the above",
        "d": "project planning",
        "answer": "hierarchical planning"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was originally called the \"imitation game\" by its creator?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "The Turing Test",
        "b": "LISP",
        "c": "The Logic Theorist",
        "d": "Cybernetics",
        "answer": "The Turing Test"
    },
    {
        "question": "Decision support programs are designed to help managers make:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "budget projections",
        "b": "visual presentations",
        "c": "business decisions",
        "d": "vacation schedules",
        "answer": "business decisions"
    },
    {
        "question": "PROLOG is an AI programming language which solves problems with a form of symbolic logic known as predicate calculus. It was developed in 1972 at the University of Marseilles by a team of specialists. Can you name the person who headed this team?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Alain Colmerauer",
        "b": "Nicklaus Wirth",
        "c": "Seymour Papert",
        "d": "John McCarthy",
        "answer": "Alain Colmerauer"
    },
    {
        "question": "Programming a robot by physically moving it through the trajectory you want it to follow is called:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "contact sensing control",
        "b": "continuous-path control",
        "c": "robot vision control",
        "d": "pick-and-place control",
        "answer": "continuous-path control"
    },
    {
        "question": "To invoke the LISP system, you must enter\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "AI",
        "b": "LISP",
        "c": "CL (Common Lisp)",
        "d": "both b and c",
        "answer": "both b and c"
    },
    {
        "question": "DEC advertises that it helped to create \"the world's first expert system routinely used in an industrial environment,\" called XCON or:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "PDP-11",
        "b": "Rl",
        "c": "VAX",
        "d": "MAGNOM",
        "answer": "Rl"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to the invention of time sharing, the prevalent method of computer access was:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "batch processing",
        "b": "telecommunication",
        "c": "remote access",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "batch processing"
    },
    {
        "question": "Seymour Papert of the MIT AI lab created a programming environment for children called:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "BASIC",
        "b": "LOGO",
        "c": "MYCIN",
        "d": "FORTRAN",
        "answer": "LOGO"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Strategic Computing Program is a project of the:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency",
        "b": "National Science Foundation",
        "c": "Jet Propulsion Laboratory",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency"
    },
    {
        "question": "The original LISP machines produced by both LMI and Symbolics were based on research performed at:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "CMU",
        "b": "MIT",
        "c": "Stanford University",
        "d": "RAMD",
        "answer": "MIT"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the addition 3 + 2 is entered as\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "3 + 2",
        "b": "3 add 2",
        "c": "3 + 2 =",
        "d": "(+ 3 2)",
        "answer": "(+ 3 2)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Weak AI is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "the embodiment of human intellectual capabilities within a computer.",
        "b": "a set of computer programs that produce output that would be considered to reflect intelligence if it were generated by humans.",
        "c": "the study of mental faculties through the use of mental models implemented on a computer.",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "the study of mental faculties through the use of mental models implemented on a computer."
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the function assigns the symbol x to y is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "(setq y x)",
        "b": "(set y = 'x')",
        "c": "(setq y = 'x')",
        "d": "(setq y 'x')",
        "answer": "(setq y 'x')"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the function returns t if <object> is a CONS cell and nil otherwise:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "(cons <object>)",
        "b": "(consp <object>)",
        "c": "(eq <object>)",
        "d": "(cous = <object>)",
        "answer": "(consp <object>)"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a rule-based system, procedural domain knowledge is in the form of:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "production rules",
        "b": "rule interpreters",
        "c": "meta-rules",
        "d": "control rules",
        "answer": "production rules"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a robot can alter its own trajectory in response to external conditions, it is considered to be:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "intelligent",
        "b": "mobile",
        "c": "open loop",
        "d": "non-servo",
        "answer": "intelligent"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the leading American robotics centers is the Robotics Institute located at:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "CMU",
        "b": "MIT",
        "c": "RAND",
        "d": "SRI",
        "answer": "CMU"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the function returns the first element of a list Is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "set",
        "b": "car",
        "c": "first",
        "d": "second",
        "answer": "car"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nils Nilsson headed a team at SRI that created a mobile robot named:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Robitics",
        "b": "Dedalus",
        "c": "Shakey",
        "d": "Vax",
        "answer": "Shakey"
    },
    {
        "question": "An AI technique that allows computers to understand associations and relationships between objects and events is called:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "heuristic processing",
        "b": "cognitive science",
        "c": "relative symbolism",
        "d": "pattern matching",
        "answer": "pattern matching"
    },
    {
        "question": "The new organization established to implement the Fifth Generation Project is called:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "ICOT (Institute for New Generation Computer Technology)",
        "b": "MITI (Ministry of International Trade and Industry)",
        "c": "MCC (Microelectronics and Computer Technology Corporation)",
        "d": "SCP (Stategic Computing Program)",
        "answer": "ICOT (Institute for New Generation Computer Technology)"
    },
    {
        "question": "The field that investigates the mechanics of human intelligence is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "history",
        "b": "cognitive science",
        "c": "psychology",
        "d": "sociology",
        "answer": "cognitive science"
    },
    {
        "question": "A problem is first connected to its proposed solution during the _____ stage.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "conceptualization",
        "b": "identification",
        "c": "formalization",
        "d": "implementation",
        "answer": "formalization"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the computer program that simulates the thought processes of human beings?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Human logic",
        "b": "Expert reason",
        "c": "Expert system",
        "d": "Personal information",
        "answer": "Expert system"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the computer program that contains the distilled knowledge of an expert?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Data base management system",
        "b": "Management information System",
        "c": "Expert system",
        "d": "Artificial intelligence",
        "answer": "Expert system"
    },
    {
        "question": "Claude Shannon described the operation of electronic switching circuits with a system of mathematical logic called:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "LISP",
        "b": "XLISP",
        "c": "Boolean algebra",
        "d": "neural networking",
        "answer": "Boolean algebra"
    },
    {
        "question": "A computer program that contains expertise in a particular domain is called an:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "intelligent planner",
        "b": "automatic processor",
        "c": "expert system",
        "d": "operational symbolizer",
        "answer": "expert system"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ambiguity may be caused by:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "syntactic ambiguity",
        "b": "multiple word meanings",
        "c": "unclear antecedents",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company offers the LISP machine considered to be \"the most powerful symbolic processor available\"?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "LMI",
        "b": "Symbolics",
        "c": "Xerox",
        "d": "Texas Instruments",
        "answer": "Symbolics"
    },
    {
        "question": "What of the following is considered to be a pivotal event in the history of AI.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "1949, Donald O, The organization of Behaviour,",
        "b": "1950, Computing Machinery and Intelligence.",
        "c": "1956, Dartmouth University Conference Organized by John McCarthy",
        "d": "1961, Computer and Computer Sense.",
        "answer": "1956, Dartmouth University Conference Organized by John McCarthy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Natural language processing is divided into the two subfields of:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "symbolic and numeric",
        "b": "time and motion",
        "c": "algorithmic and heuristic",
        "d": "understanding and generation",
        "answer": "understanding and generation"
    },
    {
        "question": "High-resolution, bit-mapped displays are useful for displaying:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "clearer characters",
        "b": "graphics",
        "c": "more characters",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "A bidirectional feedback loop links computer modelling with:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "artificial science",
        "b": "heuristic processing",
        "c": "human intelligence",
        "d": "cognitive science",
        "answer": "cognitive science"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following have people traditionally done better than computers?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "recognizing relative importance",
        "b": "finding similarities",
        "c": "resolving ambiguity",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the function evaluates both <variable> and <object> is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "set",
        "b": "setq",
        "c": "add",
        "d": "eva",
        "answer": "set"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of actuator generates a good deal of power but tends to be messy?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "electric",
        "b": "hydraulic",
        "c": "pneumatic",
        "d": "(B) and (c) above",
        "answer": "hydraulic"
    },
    {
        "question": "Research scientists all over the world are taking steps towards building computers with circuits patterned after the complex inter connections existing among the human brain's nerve cells. What name is given to such type of computers?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Intelligent computers",
        "b": "Supercomputers",
        "c": "Neural network computers",
        "d": "Smart computers",
        "answer": "Neural network computers"
    },
    {
        "question": "The hardware features of LISP machines generally include:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "large memory and a high-speed processor",
        "b": "letter-quality printers and 8-inch disk drives",
        "c": "a mouse and a specialized keyboard",
        "d": "both (a) and (c)",
        "answer": "both (a) and (c)"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1985, the famous chess player David Levy beat a world champion chess program in four straight games by using orthodox moves that confused the program. What was the name of the chess program?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Kaissa",
        "b": "CRAY BLITZ",
        "c": "Golf",
        "d": "DIGDUG",
        "answer": "CRAY BLITZ"
    },
    {
        "question": "The explanation facility of an expert system may be used to:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "construct a diagnostic model",
        "b": "expedite the debugging process",
        "c": "explain the system's reasoning process",
        "d": "both (b) and (c)",
        "answer": "both (b) and (c)"
    },
    {
        "question": "A process that is repeated, evaluated, and refined is called:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "diagnostic",
        "b": "descriptive",
        "c": "interpretive",
        "d": "iterative",
        "answer": "iterative"
    },
    {
        "question": "Visual clues that are helpful in computer vision include:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "colour and motion",
        "b": "depth and texture",
        "c": "height and weight",
        "d": "a and b above",
        "answer": "a and b above"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the function X (x). (2x+l) would be rendered as\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "(lambda (x) (+(*2 x)l))",
        "b": "(lambda (x) (+1 (* 2x)",
        "c": "(+ lambda (x) 1 (*2x))",
        "d": "(* lambda(x) (+2x1)",
        "answer": "(lambda (x) (+(*2 x)l))"
    },
    {
        "question": "A natural language generation program must decide:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "what to say",
        "b": "when to say something",
        "c": "why it is being used",
        "d": "both (a) and (b)",
        "answer": "both (a) and (b)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is considered to be the \"father\" of artificial intelligence?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Fisher Ada",
        "b": "John McCarthy",
        "c": "Allen Newell",
        "d": "Alan Turning",
        "answer": "John McCarthy"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following areas may ICAI programs prove to be useful?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "educational institutions",
        "b": "corporations",
        "c": "department of Defence",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "A network with named nodes and labeled arcs that can be used to represent certain natural language grammars to facilitate parsing.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Tree Network",
        "b": "Star Network",
        "c": "Transition Network",
        "d": "Complete Network",
        "answer": "Transition Network"
    },
    {
        "question": "A series of AI systems developed by Pat Langley to explore the role of heuristics in scientific discovery.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "RAMD",
        "b": "BACON",
        "c": "MIT",
        "d": "DU",
        "answer": "BACON"
    },
    {
        "question": "A.M. turing developed a technique for determining whether a computer could or could not demonstrate the artificial Intelligence,, Presently, this technique is called\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Turing Test",
        "b": "Algorithm",
        "c": "Boolean Algebra",
        "d": "Logarithm",
        "answer": "Turing Test"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Personal Consultant knowledge base contain information in the form of:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "parameters",
        "b": "contexts",
        "c": "production rules",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which approach to speech recognition avoids the problem caused by the variation in speech patterns among different speakers?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Continuous speech recognition",
        "b": "Isolated word recognition",
        "c": "Connected word recognition",
        "d": "Speaker-dependent recognition",
        "answer": "Speaker-dependent recognition"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following, is a component of an expert system?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "inference engine",
        "b": "knowledge base",
        "c": "user interface",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "A computer vision technique that relies on image templates is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "edge detection",
        "b": "binocular vision",
        "c": "model-based vision",
        "d": "robot vision",
        "answer": "model-based vision"
    },
    {
        "question": "DARPA, the agency that has funded a great deal of American AI research, is part of the Department of:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Defense",
        "b": "Energy",
        "c": "Education",
        "d": "Justice",
        "answer": "Defense"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these schools was not among the early leaders in AI research?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Dartmouth University",
        "b": "Harvard University",
        "c": "Massachusetts Institute of Technology",
        "d": "Stanford University",
        "answer": "Harvard University"
    },
    {
        "question": "A certain Professor at the Stanford University coined the word 'artificial intelligence' in 1956 at a conference held at Dartmouth college. Can you name the Professor?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "David Levy",
        "b": "John McCarthy",
        "c": "Joseph Weizenbaum",
        "d": "Hans Berliner",
        "answer": "John McCarthy"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the function (copy-list <list>)\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "returns a new list that is equal to <list> by copying the top-level element of <list>",
        "b": "returns the length of <list>",
        "c": "returns t if <list> is empty.",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "returns a new list that is equal to <list> by copying the top-level element of <list>"
    },
    {
        "question": "LISP machines also are known as:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "AI workstations",
        "b": "time-sharing terminals",
        "c": "super mini computers",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "AI workstations"
    },
    {
        "question": "Natural language processing can be divided into the two subfields of:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "context and expectations",
        "b": "generation and understanding",
        "c": "semantics of pragmatics",
        "d": "recognition and synthesis",
        "answer": "generation and understanding"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many ALU(s) is\/are control by one control unit is SIMD (single instruction stream, multiple data stream) architecture?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "one or more ALUs",
        "b": "One ALU",
        "c": "Only two ALU .",
        "d": "Impossible to say",
        "answer": "one or more ALUs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following function returns t if the object is a number in LISP?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "(number <object>)",
        "b": "(numberp <object>)",
        "c": "(numericp <object>)",
        "d": "(numeric <object>)",
        "answer": "(numberp <object>)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following have computers traditionally done better than people?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "storing information",
        "b": "responding flexibly",
        "c": "computing numerically",
        "d": "both (a) and (c)",
        "answer": "both (a) and (c)"
    },
    {
        "question": "The characteristics of the computer system capable of thinking, reasoning and learning is known is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "machine intelligence",
        "b": "human intelligence",
        "c": "artificial intelligence",
        "d": "virtual intelligence",
        "answer": "artificial intelligence"
    },
    {
        "question": "What part of the manufacturing process relate to each stage of the process and to the process as a whole?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "field service",
        "b": "design",
        "c": "distribution",
        "d": "project management",
        "answer": "project management"
    },
    {
        "question": "The area of AI that investigates methods of facilitating communication between people and computers is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "natural language processing",
        "b": "symbolic processing",
        "c": "decision support",
        "d": "robotics",
        "answer": "natural language processing"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 16th century, a Czech rabbi reportedly created a living clay man whose name has become a synonym for an artificial human. The clay man's name was:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Frankenstein",
        "b": "Golem",
        "c": "Paracelsus",
        "d": "Hal",
        "answer": "Golem"
    },
    {
        "question": "For speech understanding systems to gain widespread acceptance in office automation, they must feature:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "speaker independence",
        "b": "speaker dependence",
        "c": "isolated word recognition",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "speaker independence"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the function returns the list that results after the first element is removed (the rest f the list), is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "car",
        "b": "last",
        "c": "cons",
        "d": "cdr",
        "answer": "cdr"
    },
    {
        "question": "Output segments of AI programming contain(s)\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "printed language and synthesized speech",
        "b": "Manipulation of physical object",
        "c": "Locomotion",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "LISP was created by:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "John McCarthy",
        "b": "Marvin Minsky",
        "c": "Alan Turing",
        "d": "Allen Newell and Herbert Simon",
        "answer": "John McCarthy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Expert Ease was developed under the direction of:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "John McCarthy",
        "b": "Donald Michie",
        "c": "Lofti Zadeh",
        "d": "Alan Turing",
        "answer": "Donald Michie"
    },
    {
        "question": "An AI system developed by Terry A. Winograd to permit an interactive dialogue about a domain he called blocks-world.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "SHRDLU",
        "b": "SIMD",
        "c": "BACON",
        "d": "STUDENT",
        "answer": "SHRDLU"
    },
    {
        "question": "MLMenu, a natural language interface for the TI Explorer, is similar to:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Ethernet",
        "b": "NaturalLink",
        "c": "PROLOG",
        "d": "the Personal Consultant",
        "answer": "NaturalLink"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many control unit(s) is\/are available in SISD (single data stream, single data stream) architecture?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "one",
        "b": "two",
        "c": "more than one",
        "d": "Mone",
        "answer": "one"
    },
    {
        "question": "Strong AI is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "the embodiment of human intellectual capabilities within a computer.",
        "b": "a set of computer programs that produce output that would be considered to reflect intelligence if it were generated by humans.",
        "c": "the study of mental faculties through the use of mental models implemented on a computer.",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "the embodiment of human intellectual capabilities within a computer."
    },
    {
        "question": "The traditional way to exit and LISP system is to enter\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "quit",
        "b": "exit",
        "c": "bye",
        "d": "ok",
        "answer": "exit"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which of the following situations might a blind search be acceptable?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "real-life situation",
        "b": "complex game",
        "c": "small search space",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "small search space"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the function (endp <list>)\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "returns a new list that is equal to <list> by copying the top-level element of <list>",
        "b": "returns the length of <list>",
        "c": "returns t if <list> is empty.",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "returns t if <list> is empty."
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, which of the following function assigns the value 10 to the symbol a?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "(setq a 10)",
        "b": "(a = b) where b = 10",
        "c": "(a = 10) (d) (setq 10 a)",
        "d": "None of the above",
        "answer": "(setq a 10)"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the atom that stands for \"False\" is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "t",
        "b": "nil",
        "c": "y",
        "d": "time",
        "answer": "nil"
    },
    {
        "question": "The expert system developed at MIT to solve mathematical problems is known as:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "RAND",
        "b": "ISIS",
        "c": "MACSYMA",
        "d": "MOLGEN",
        "answer": "MACSYMA"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which approach to speech recognition avoids the problem caused by the differences in the way words are pronounced according to context?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "continuous speech recognition",
        "b": "connected word recognition",
        "c": "isolated word recognition",
        "d": "speaker-dependent recognition",
        "answer": "isolated word recognition"
    },
    {
        "question": "A KES knowledge base contains information in the form of:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "associations",
        "b": "actions",
        "c": "free ",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "In AI programming, a list may contain:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "cells",
        "b": "fields",
        "c": "pointers",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the function (minusp (-20 4 8 8 1) returns\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "T",
        "b": "F",
        "c": "NIL",
        "d": "-20",
        "answer": "T"
    },
    {
        "question": "Special programs that assist programmers are called:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "heuristic processors",
        "b": "symbolic programmers",
        "c": "intelligent programming tools",
        "d": "program recognizers",
        "answer": "intelligent programming tools"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the English Philosopher Thomas Hobbes could be called 'grandfather' of artificial intelligence, then who could be called its father?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "A.M. Turning",
        "b": "John McCarthy",
        "c": "Allen Newell",
        "d": "Herbert Simon",
        "answer": "A.M. Turning"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the function returns t if <integer> is even and nil otherwise:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "(evenp <integer>)",
        "b": "(even <integer>)",
        "c": "(numeven <integer>)",
        "d": "(numnevenp <integer>)",
        "answer": "(evenp <integer>)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is an advantage of using an expert system development tool?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "imposed structure",
        "b": "knowledge engineering assistance",
        "c": "rapid prototyping",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "An AI system developed by Daniel Bobrow to read and solve algebra word problems\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "SHRDLU",
        "b": "SIMD",
        "c": "BACON",
        "d": "STUDENT",
        "answer": "STUDENT"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"Turing Machine\" showed that you could use a\/an _____ system to program any algorithmic task.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "binary",
        "b": "electro-chemical",
        "c": "recursive",
        "d": "semantic",
        "answer": "binary"
    },
    {
        "question": "MCC is investigating the improvement of the relationship between people and computers through a technology called:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "computer-aided design",
        "b": "human factors",
        "c": "parallel processing",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "human factors"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first widely-used commercial form of Artificial Intelligence (Al) is being used in many popular products like microwave ovens, automobiles and plug in circuit boards for desktop PCs. It allows machines to handle vague information with a deftness that mimics human intuition. What is the name of this AI?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Boolean logic",
        "b": "Human logic",
        "c": "Fuzzy logic",
        "d": "Functional logic",
        "answer": "Fuzzy logic"
    },
    {
        "question": "In his landmark book Cybernetics, Norbert Wiener suggested a way of modeling scientific phenomena using not energy, but:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "mathematics",
        "b": "intelligence",
        "c": "information",
        "d": "history",
        "answer": "information"
    },
    {
        "question": "Input segments of AI programming contain(s)\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "sound",
        "b": "smell",
        "c": "touch",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "The applications in the Strategic Computing Program include:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "battle management",
        "b": "autonomous systems",
        "c": "pilot's associate",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the function evaluates <object> and assigns this value to the unevaluated <sconst>.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "(constant <sconst> <object>)",
        "b": "(defconstant <sconst> <object>)",
        "c": "(eva <sconst> <object>)",
        "d": "(eva <object> <sconst>)",
        "answer": "(defconstant <sconst> <object>)"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary interactive method of communication used by humans is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "reading",
        "b": "writing",
        "c": "speaking",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "speaking"
    },
    {
        "question": "Elementary linguistic units which are smaller than words are:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "allophones",
        "b": "phonemes",
        "c": "syllables",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the atom that stands for \"true\" is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "t",
        "b": "ml",
        "c": "y",
        "d": "time",
        "answer": "t"
    },
    {
        "question": "A mouse device may be:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "electro-chemical",
        "b": "mechanical",
        "c": "optical",
        "d": "both b and c",
        "answer": "both b and c"
    },
    {
        "question": "An expert system differs from a database program in that only an expert system:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "contains declarative knowledge",
        "b": "contains procedural knowledge",
        "c": "features the retrieval of stored information",
        "d": "expects users to draw their own conclusions",
        "answer": "contains procedural knowledge"
    },
    {
        "question": "Arthur Samuel is linked inextricably with a program that played:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "checkers",
        "b": "chess",
        "c": "cricket",
        "d": "football",
        "answer": "checkers"
    },
    {
        "question": "Natural language understanding is used in:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "natural language interfaces",
        "b": "natural language front ends",
        "c": "text understanding systems",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are examples of software development tools?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "debuggers",
        "b": "editors",
        "c": "assemblers, compilers and interpreters",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first AI programming language was called:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "BASIC",
        "b": "FORTRAN",
        "c": "IPL",
        "d": "LISP",
        "answer": "IPL"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Personal Consultant is based on:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "EMYCIN",
        "b": "OPS5+",
        "c": "XCON",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "The conference that launched the AI revolution in 1956 was held at:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Dartmouth",
        "b": "Harvard",
        "c": "New York",
        "d": "Stanford",
        "answer": "Dartmouth"
    },
    {
        "question": "Texas Instruments Incorporated produces a low-cost LISP machine called:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "The Computer-Based Consultant",
        "b": "The Explorer",
        "c": "Smalltalk",
        "d": "The Personal Consultant",
        "answer": "The Explorer"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a top-level function is entered, the LISP processor do(es)\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "It reads the function entered",
        "b": "It evaluates the function and the function's operands",
        "c": "It prints the results returned by the function.",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "One method of programming a computer to exhibit human intelligence is called modeling or:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "simulation",
        "b": "cognitization",
        "c": "duplication",
        "d": "psychic amelioration",
        "answer": "simulation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Graphic interfaces were first used in a Xerox product called:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "InterLISP",
        "b": "Ethernet",
        "c": "Smalltalk",
        "d": "ZetaLISP",
        "answer": "Smalltalk"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Al researcher who co-authored both the Handbook of Artificial Intelligence and The Fifth Generation is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Bruce Lee",
        "b": "Randy Davis",
        "c": "Ed Feigenbaum",
        "d": "Mark Fox",
        "answer": "Ed Feigenbaum"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is being investigated as a means of automating the creation of a knowledge base?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "automatic knowledge acquisition",
        "b": "simpler tools",
        "c": "discovery of new concepts",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "The CAI (Computer-Assisted Instruction) technique based on programmed instruction is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "frame-based CAI",
        "b": "generative CAI",
        "c": "problem-solving CAI",
        "d": "intelligent CAI",
        "answer": "frame-based CAI"
    },
    {
        "question": "A robot's \"arm\" is also known as its:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "end effector",
        "b": "actuator",
        "c": "manipulator",
        "d": "servomechanism",
        "answer": "manipulator"
    },
    {
        "question": "KEE is a product of:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Teknowledge",
        "b": "IntelliCorpn",
        "c": "Texas Instruments",
        "d": "Tech knowledge",
        "answer": "IntelliCorpn"
    },
    {
        "question": "Computers normally solve problem by breaking them down into a series of yes-or-no decisions represented by 1s and 0s. What is the name of the logic that allows computers to assign numerical values that fail somewhere between 0 and 1?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Human logic",
        "b": "Fuzzy logic",
        "c": "Boolean logic",
        "d": "Operational logic",
        "answer": "Fuzzy logic"
    },
    {
        "question": "The component of an ICAI (Intelligent Computer-Asslsted Instruction) presenting information to the student is the:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "student model",
        "b": "problem-solving expertise",
        "c": "tutoring module",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "tutoring module"
    },
    {
        "question": "The company that grew out of research at the MIT AI lab is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "AI corp",
        "b": "LMI",
        "c": "Symbolics",
        "d": "both (b) and (c)",
        "answer": "both (b) and (c)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique is being investigated as an approach to automatic programming?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "generative CAI",
        "b": "specification by example",
        "c": "All of the above",
        "d": "non-hierarchical planning",
        "answer": "specification by example"
    },
    {
        "question": "One definition of AI focuses on problem-solving methods that process:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "smell",
        "b": "symbols",
        "c": "touch",
        "d": "algorithms",
        "answer": "symbols"
    },
    {
        "question": "Artificial intelligence is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "the embodiment of human intellectual capabilities within a computer.",
        "b": "a set of computer programs that produce output that would be considered to reflect intelligence if it were generated by humans.",
        "c": "the study of mental faculties through the use of mental models implemented on a computer.",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary method that people use to sense their environment is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "reading",
        "b": "writing",
        "c": "speaking",
        "d": "seeing",
        "answer": "seeing"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Newell and Simon program that proved theorems of Principia Mathematica was:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Elementary Perceiver",
        "b": "General Problem Solver",
        "c": "Logic Theorist",
        "d": "Boolean Algebra",
        "answer": "Logic Theorist"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the function assigns . the value of a to b is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "(setq a b)",
        "b": "(setq b a )",
        "c": "(b = a)",
        "d": "(set b = a)",
        "answer": "(setq b a )"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cray X-MP, IBM 3090 and connection machine can he characterized as\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "SISD",
        "b": "SIMD",
        "c": "MISD",
        "d": "MIMD",
        "answer": "SIMD"
    },
    {
        "question": "In LISP, the function (list-length <list>)\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "returns a new list that is equal to <list> by copying the top-level element of <list>",
        "b": "returns the length of <list>",
        "c": "returns t if <list> is empty.",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "returns the length of <list>"
    },
    {
        "question": "ART (Automatic Reasoning Tool) is designed to be used on:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "LISP machines",
        "b": "personal computers",
        "c": "microcomputers",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "LISP machines"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which particular generation of computers is associated with artificial intelligence?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Second",
        "b": "Fourth",
        "c": "Fifth",
        "d": "Third",
        "answer": "Fifth"
    },
    {
        "question": "Shaping teaching techniques to fit the learning patterns of individual students is the goal of:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "decision support",
        "b": "automatic programming",
        "c": "intelligent computer-assisted instruction",
        "d": "expert systems",
        "answer": "intelligent computer-assisted instruction"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following function returns t If the object is a symbol m LISP?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "(* <object>)",
        "b": "(symbolp <object>)",
        "c": "(nonnumeric <object>)",
        "d": "(constantp <object>)",
        "answer": "(symbolp <object>)"
    },
    {
        "question": "The symbols used in describing the syntax of a programming language are\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "0",
        "b": "{}",
        "c": "\"\"",
        "d": "<>",
        "answer": "<>"
    },
    {
        "question": "The integrated circuit was invented by Jack Kilby of:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "MIT",
        "b": "Texas Instruments",
        "c": "Xerox",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "Texas Instruments"
    },
    {
        "question": "People overcome natural language problems by:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "grouping attributes into frames",
        "b": "understanding ideas in context",
        "c": "identifying with familiar situations",
        "d": "both (b) and (c)",
        "answer": "both (b) and (c)"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Cedar, BBN Butterfly, Cosmic Cube and Hypercube machine can be characterized as\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "SISD",
        "b": "MIMD",
        "c": "SIMD",
        "d": "MISD",
        "answer": "MIMD"
    }
]